8667594892

janani244@yahoo.in

12/07/1987

## **OBJECTIVE**

Successful medical billing and coding professional with over 13 years of experience in healthcare. Iam seeking a position with a company or facility where I can apply my knowledge and expertise in the field of Medical insurance Billing and Coding.

### **SKILLS**

Claims Entry and Payment Posting
Account Receivables and Ar Calling
Patient Statements
Client Management
Multi Specialties
Team Leadership
Training and Development
Files and Reports Management
HIPAA Compliance

# JANANI KUMAR

**Bangalore** 

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## FLATWORLD HEALTHCARE SERVICES PVT LTD

APRIL 2023 - JULY 2023

TEAM LEAD AR

Specially Worked

. Internal Medicine

Software Worked

- . All scripts
- . E CLINICAL WORKS

Handled Charge Entry, Payment Posting and AR team

# EXPRIMUNT MEDICAL BILLING PRIVATE LIMITED - Bengaluru, DEC 2021 - MARCH Karnataka 2023

ACCOUNT RECEIVABLE SPECIALIST

Specialty Worked

. Internal Medicine

Software Worked

. Kareo

Handled Internal Medicine End to End process.

# Omega Healthcare Management Services Pvt Ltd - Bengaluru, Karnataka

Feb 2020 - March 2021

**TEAM MANAGER - BI** 

Specialty Worked

. Internal Medicine

Software Worked

. All Scripts

- . BI works for efforts to increase revenue and reduce operating costs.
- . The Key Performance Indicators Report dashboards.
- . The Insurance Analysis Report.
- . Clearinghouse Rejections.
- . Insurance Analysis Report.

### INFOTECH GLOBAL INDIA LTD - Bengaluru, Karnataka

March 2017 - August 2019

LEAD ANALYST

Specialty Worked

- . Internal Medicine
- . Paediatrics
- . Pulmonary Critical Care

Software Worked

. EHI

The Team Leader job involves managing and guiding a team of charge, payment and AR associates who will be responsible for analysis of receivables due from healthcare insurance companies and initiation of necessary follow-up actions to get reimbursed. The work includes a combination of voice and non-voice follow-up along with undertaking appropriate denial and appeal management protocol.

- . Responsible to set up to the client practices  $% \left( 1\right) =\left( 1\right) \left( 1\right$
- . Ensure targeted collections are met on daily/monthly basis.
- . Training and Practice updates with Team members.
- . Client communication and Follow up regarding the billing issues.
- . Generating reports and meeting with client on monthly basis.
- . Independently managed a team of 20 members.
- . Develop process to improve productivity and quality of the team.
- . Tracking and maintaining metrics for a variety of data includes attendance and Productivity.

### SR AR ANALYST

Specialty Worked

- Internal Medicine
  Cardiology
  paediatrics

- . Pulmonary Critical Care
- . Nephrology
- . OBGYN

### Software Worked

. E CLINICAL WORKS and EHI

Handled Multi-speciality process in denial management with End to end process.

## ATS HEALTHCARE - Chennai, Tamilnadu

April 2010 - July 2014

AR ANALYST

Specialty Worked . İnternal Medicine

Software Worked

. KAREO and E CLINICAL WORKS

Handled Internal medicine with End to End process ( Claims auditing; EOB Tally; Accounts Receivables; Patient Statements; Payer and Clearing house rejections.

## **EDUCATION**

**Madras University** Passing Year - 2008

Bcom

Grades : 73 %

GOOD SHEPHERD MATRIC HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL Passing Year - 2004

HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

Grades : 70 %

NKS VIVEKANANDA VIDYALAYA CBSE

Passing Year - 2002

SECONDARY SCHOOL

Grades : 47 %